Arsham Arya

Software Engineer

Email: Arshamalh@gmail.com Location: Iran, Tehran

Linkedin: Linkedin/in/arshamalh Phone: +98 (930) 949 8445

GitHub: Github.com/arshamalh Legal Name: Mohammad Reza Karimi

Summary

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience mainly as a **Backend Engineer** designing and developing **scalable**, **maintainable**, and **efficient** systems in FinTech, Ride-hailing (Snapp!), E-commerce, and Social Media.

Collaborated as a **DevOps** Engineer, **Frontend** Developer, and **ETL** Engineer when necessary.

Mentoring & Inspiring people to start or grow their careers is one of my greatest hobbies & glories.

Skills

Primary Programming Languages: Go (golang), JavaScript (Node.js).

Databases: PostgreSQL, Redis, MongoDB, MySQL.

DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift, Gitlab CICD, Helm.

Tools: Git, Node.js, Kafka, RabbitMQ, gRPC, NATS.

Architecture: Microservices, Event-Driven, System Design, SOA, Modular Monolith.

Some Other Technical Skills: Python, PHP, TDD, GitHub Actions, Clean Code, Design Patterns, Blockchain, Smart contracts (Solidity), Web3, Fiber, Gin, Testify, Echo, Expressjs, Socket.io, Sveltejs, JQuery, ReactJS, NextJS, SOLID, OOP, Prometheus, Grafana, ELK (elastic stack).

Languages: English (Fluent), German (Intermediate, In progress), Persian (Native), Luri (Native).

Experiences

Software Engineer @ Snapp! (Iran, Tehran)

Dec 2022 - Present

Snapp is the leading Ride-hailing application in Iran with over 48m users, 3.7m drivers, and 3+ million rides per day.

- Implemented event-driven architecture on services to increase reliability.
- Contributed to **dismantling** a huge legacy monolith service written in PHP.
- Contributed to designing and developing a highly efficient **Bulk job handler**.
- Helmified Services and Updated GitLab CI/CD pipelines and K8s resources to improve the team's workflow.
- Constantly maintaining **OpenShift** clusters including migrating services from **OKD3** to **OKD4** and from **ROSA** to Self-hosted, monitoring them, and fixing issues when needed.
- Ownership of user management and notification service of the back-office team, including developing features, improving code quality, and increasing test coverage, fixing bugs, monitoring, shipping to production, etc.
- Collaborated with other teams to build tools and solutions to increase their productivity.

Technical Lead @ Norotech (Start-Up) (Remote - Part-time)

July 2022 - Present

Norotech is a B2B start-up providing and designing tech solutions to other start-ups

- Writing Technical Proposals, and close collaboration with stakeholders to clarify and improve business requirements.
- Collaborating with HR teams for interviewing, and hiring the first group of engineers, shaping cultures and teams.
- Onboarding new team members and helping junior developers get a good grasp of the code base.
- Delegating tasks, reviewing PRs, and leading technical teams towards our business goals.
- Giving constructive feedback and resolving conflicts when required.

Software Engineer @ Binj (US, West Hollywood - Remote)

Nov 2021 - Oct 2022 (1 year)

Binj was a social media (then pivoted to a B2B data provider) platform focused on movies.

- Developed a full-featured **Scrapper Platform** including 12 scrappers, orchestrator, API gateway, and databases capable of quickly gathering information about movies from millions of pages across the web for AI team usage.
- Built a **Bot colony** capable of handling hundreds of bots for promoting social media content on Twitter, Instagram, etc., according to custom algorithms, manual requests, or AI service commands received from **API** endpoints.
- Created a **Task Management Platform** to show human agents some tasks, verify their duties, and give them credit.
- Made UI for monitoring, controlling, and having a comprehensive overview of data flow and user interactions.

Software Engineer @ BonyanTeam (Coinvela) (Iran, Tehran)

Jan 2019 - Aug 2021 (2 years & 8 months)

Financial B2C Company focused on cryptocurrency trading utilities.

- Developed a Copy trader for trading on predefined prices or leaders' moves.
- Architected an Autotrader engine taking custom trading algorithms.
- Designed & constantly maintained services constructing Coinvela.
- Converted trading strategies from pine script to JS equivalents.
- Collaborated with the frontend team to make Panels controlling Copy Trader, Autotrader, and Coinvela.
- Created a Crypto wallet for payments (supporting BTC, ETH, and TRX).

Software Developer @ SangSefid (Iran, Markazi - Part-time)

Jan 2017 - Jan 2019 (2 years)

Computer service center

- Increased 5x revenue by Developing **UI automation tools**.
- Improved Customer satisfaction by making various **Telegram bots**.
- Enhanced productivity by Architecting Accounting and Management software.

Projects

ShikoPik: Full-featured B2C & C2C eCommerce for fashion and clothes. (**Private**) **Kari:** A platform to connect health centers to their required consultants. (**Private**)

Twigo: Go library for the Twitter API. (Link - open-source)

Blogo: Simple Blog project for educational purposes. (Link - open-source)

Dockeroller: ChatOps project for controlling docker through chat applications. (Link - open-source) **Podcribe:** Podcast crawler - transcriber - translator with Telegram bot and UI. (Closed-source for now)

Volunteering

- Contributing to **open-source** projects, and open-sourcing my own projects.
- Programming Course instructor with 500+ downloads.
- Managing a community of Engineers with more than 900+ engineers.
- Mentoring 20+ people all the way along to find a software engineering job.
- Answering and asking questions on Stackoverflow/ArshamArya.
- Writing technical articles on **Dev.to/arshamalh**.

Education

Arak University, Iran - Associate of Mechanical Engineering (2017 - 2020)

- Cut down more than 80% of the paperwork by making a full-featured Gearbox design application.
- Made Thermocal application for thermodynamic calculations.
- 1st Student in our University Rankings